Carman Terblanche

Cape Town, South Africa •carmanillustrations@gmail.com • +27 727 072 657

•<u>LinkedIn</u> •Website

Carman has 5+ years experience in the Video Editing space on an informal /freelance basis and has worked with small companies in a corporate Video Editing role. He has basic knowledge of After Effects with 1+ years accumulative experience in creating motion graphics for various purposes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WEST MEDIA AND MARKETING Video Editor

Remote, South Africa 2024-2024

I worked on a freelance basis for West Media and Marketing as a Junior Editor to assist in creating Social Media posts, Corporate videos and Docuseries for YouTube.

- Edited a 23-minute Docuseries episode for a client for YouTube.
- Edited multiple Social Media content for Instagram, LinkedIn and Facebook.
- Aided with loose tasks like recording voice overs and animating motion graphics.

FreeLancer Video Editor Remote, South Africa 2023-2024

Edited video content using Adobe Premiere Pro for clients based on their needs.

- Edited 3 ads for a Nail Salon (Tammy Taylor Nails).
- Successfully edited 4 scenes for director projects using Adobe Premiere Pro.
- Produced the score for a short film for ACT Cape Town using Ableton Live.
- Directed and edited 4 music videos for local artists, ensuring a cohesive visual narrative.

ORY SYSTEMS GMBH

Designer

Remote, South Africa 2022-2023

Streamlined the website design language in partnership with the lead designer, resulting in a visually cohesive and user-friendly interface that contributed to an 18% boost in conversion rates and a 20% increase in customer engagement.

- Created over 200 illustrations for web applications using Figma.
- Redesigned the illustration design language to align with the new branding, resulting in a cohesive asset grid.
- Produced motion graphics, loop animations, and video assets for the company's website.
- Designed LinkedIn ads using Figma, aligning them with the updated branding.

Utilized Typescript and HTML to update website content and illustrations.

Freelancer Remote, South Africa
Visual Artist 2021-2022

Collaborated with corporate clients to conceptualize, storyboard, and produce marketing-focused video content. Concurrently served as a photographer, crafting compelling marketing materials.

- Produced a Motion Graphic video using After Effects and Figma for Oleaintueri's product, SwiftQ.
- Created Motion Graphic videos for a local company to showcase their retail product line-up.
- Photographed wedding dresses to showcase a dress designer's new line-up.

EDUCATION

Monash University

Melbourne*, Australia

Bachelor's of Computer and Information Sciences

2017-2020

• I completed my degree with a major in Mobile Systems, and learned the fundamentals of business, software security and wireless technologies

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Video Reel
- **Technical Skills**: Adobe Premiere Pro After Effects, Studio Portrait Photography, Figma, Ableton Live, Blender, HTML/CSS
- Languages: Fluent in English (Bi-lingual), Afrikaans (Bi-lingual)
- **References**: Dewald van der Westhuizen (+27 733 634 78)